

Giovanni Olei

601-768-70256 | E: olei_giovanni@hotmail.com 85 Adiva-No.8 Persiaran Residen , Kuala Lumpur, Kuala Lumpur 52200

https://www.linkedin.com/in/giovanni-olei-3a93722

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated hotel general manager with more than 30 years of experience providing clients with the highest degree of hospitality and customer service by ensuring that facilities meet and exceed expectations. Strong leader possessing outstanding work ethic and integrity, always dedicated to meeting budget and meticulously documenting financials. Manages by leading and showing staff the rewards of pushing past their own expectations to provide the best work possible. Seeking a position with a top-tier hotel as General Manager with ability to build productive relationship across all levels of organization

SKILLS

Excellent manager who leads by example and through instilling confidence in staff, leading to higher productivity and better client satisfaction

- Strong communication skills that allow me to easily determine guest and employee concerns
- Budgeting
- Project Management
- Retail Industry Knowledge
- Teamwork/Collaboration

- Customer Service-oriented
- Business Acumen
- Skilled in principles of administration management in service industry, including strategic planning, production methods, human resources, coordination of people resources
- Excels in sales marketing, including showing, promoting, selling
- Critical thinker who uses logic reason to identify evaluate situations and their alternative solutions

WORK HISTORY

COUNTRY GENERAL MANAGER

09/2018 to 08/2019

Pyramid Continental Hotel-Opening | Juba, South Sudan

- Delighted to manage flagship of Anseba Hotel & Resorts in South Sudan Juba part of Eriango Group of Companies -Hospitality base in Dubai
- Showcase expertise in opening new hotel. Successfully transformed Pyramid
 Continental Hotel into lucrative profitable operation results varied from GOR,
 ADR, RevPAR, RGI, GOP, NOP Improvements to record levels in service quality
 and innovation through marketing/business strategies, exceptional guests'
 relation, and solid leadership

- Successfully open hotel with of \$165 for first second quota with revenue PAR at \$98. With average occupancy of 75% with profitability of 33% for first eleven months of operation
- Formulate policy and develop and implement new strategies and procedure Managed staff of up 210 employees, always striving to improve upon successful
 and positive culture evidenced by high employee morale and low turnover
- Developed and implemented new marketing and sales plan defined strategy for next 2 years
- Designed and introduced leadership development, coaching and team management model, resulting in promotion local employees into increased levels of responsibility
- Appointed to work with designer to plan new hotel in Zambia

GROUP DIRECTOR OF OPERATION & GENERAL MANAGER- 05/2015 to 08/2018

Angkor Prince Group Co, LTD - Opening | Siem Reap, Cambodia

As Group Director of Operation General Manager was directly responsible for all hotel operational changes & assured all hotel aspects for opening points were timely implemented in all details and in highest standards for J7 Hotel & Angkor Prince Group

- •Promoted after six months to manage existing company portfolio combine of 3 hotels Siem Reap, Phnom Penh, combine 440 keys
- •The first luxury Boutique hotel owned managed by Angkor Prince Group. Located close to King Resident icenter of Siem Reap. Only 20 minutes' drive to world Heritage Angkor Wat-largest Hindu Temple in world.
- •Responsible to developed comprehensive strategic development sales plan to achieve designated group sales objectives consistent with overall company along with Owners short long-term objectives
- Recruited, hired trained all staff, providing direct supervision, ongoing staff development and continuing education to employee
- Engaged in software development utilizing wide range of technological tools and industrial Ethernet-based protocols
- Evaluated employee performance monthly and coached and trained accordingly, increasing quality of work and employee retention

Achievements as GD&GM in properties:

- Property achieved record N.O.P for two consecutive years 2016 & 2017 with net profit of 38%
- Top G.O.P in F&B Revenue Hotel Group in 2017 with net profit of 29%
- Top 10 Boutique Hotels in Siem Reap by TripAdvisor 2016
- Booking.com- Guest Review Award 2017score 9.3 out of 10
- Agoda: Gold Circle Award Winner 2017 score 8.9 out of 10
- Certificate of Excellence TripAdvisor 2018 with score of 4.5 of 5

Rosewood Hotels & Resorts- Re-Branding | Abha, Saudi Arabia

- Company's Representative coordinating all of re-branding of hotels, pre-opening & construction activities of hotels & restaurants, coordinate with construction team, construction timeline act as liaison between hotel personnel, construction contractors and Syahya –Abha Palace Hotel management
 - \bullet In charge to coordinate re-branding hotel from Rosewood into local Hotel & Resorts with budget of \$19.5M
 - Reduced budgetary expenditures by effectively negotiating contracts for more advantageous terms
 - Managed budget implementations, employee reviews, training, schedules contract negotiations
 - Organized budgets, oversaw P&Ls achieved margin targets consistently to stay on track with growth plans
 - Drove year-over-year business growth while leading operations, strategic vision long-range planning
 - Led company successful product launch growth by developing initial product road map go-to-market strategy
 - Applied performance data to evaluate improve operations, target to current business conditions forecast needs

GENERAL MANAGER

02/2012 to 03/2015

Constellation Hospitality Hotel Management LLC | Mohammedia-Casablanca, Morocco

- Upon completion rebranding Avanti Hotel & Food & Beverage Complex for the Flagship property Constellation Hotels & Resorts Morocco
 - •Responsible for identification, initiation and follow-up of marketing plan at hotel. Involved in rooms & reservations, sales & marketing operational training for management teams. Worked with team of professionals on formulation and launch of new brand "Avanti Hotel" in Morocco.
 - \bullet Consecutive highest revenue & record GOP YTD, 2013-2014-2015, NOP of 38% as from revenue of \$5.6M to MTD \$ 9.2M
 - •Achieved top sales in company for two consecutive years, growing annual revenue by 8%
 - •Spearhead change management strategic turnaround for company during significant restructuring, including reducing employees from 280 to 250 to cut losses by \$600 annually
 - Hotel F&B Complex with Night Club/ Lounge Restaurant & Bar achievement of number of customers served yearly as from 46,800 to 73,800 yearly generation's revenue from \$1.63M to \$2.57M for years 2012-2013
 - •Worked closely with property owners and management teams to maximize revenues, protect enhance brand equity of this Luxury Boutique Hotel consist of 165 keys
 - Identified capitalized on community business opportunities with effective networking

- •Developed five years effective business plans to align strategic decisions with long-term objectives
- •Positioning the property amongst Top properties in Morocco in Constellation Hotels & Resorts
- •Chaired monthly Board Director meetings to identify opportunities for improvement, establish milestones tailor products to individual markets trend

GENERAL MANAGER

01/2011 to 02/2012

Louvre Hotels Group- Golden Tulip- Re-Branding | Tunis, Tunisia

- Drove year-over-year business growth while leading operations, strategic vision and long-range planned on capitalized and designed unique brand for Louvre-Golden Tulip Hotels, planned and implemented new management structure along with new service level
 - Corporate business hotel, full-service hotel with 340 employees. Rebranded and turned around 400+ room suite hotel, 5 restaurants, 2 bars, with 12 meeting banquet & facilities, and developed two (2) new restaurants concepts with \$2 million budget
 - Managed, supported and grew business relationships with existing accounts and developed strategies to increase sales and revenue
 - Turned around hotel income from \$1.5M (2012) to MTD revenue \$2.9M with GOP of 19.5% MTD
 - Elevated guest quality performance review score of 45% overall to 89% YTD
 - Provided leadership vision, direction, development and maintenance of multiple complex and high priority contracts between company and business partners, vendors and suppliers

GENERAL MANAGER

05/2007 to 11/2010

Louvre Hotels Group-Golden Tulip | Amman, Jordan

- •Acquired by Kuwait Financial Group Alia Airport Hotel with 330 keys was appointed General Manager with directly responsible with budget of \$12 million for rebranding Flagship five start Golden Tulip Hotel Group Amman -Jordan within twelve months.
 - Determined property facility with Chief Engineer to provide Architect Interior
 Designer new concept/criteria for entire hotel services
 - Organized budgets, oversaw P&Ls and achieved margin targets consistently to stay on track with growth plans
 - Administer operation capital budgets and manage strategy operations of hotel to ensure profitability return on owner investment
 - Strategically re-negotiating current collective bargaining agreement with airline/layover packages
 - Re-gaining airline crew, leisure, group and FIT stopover travellers guests, expanding MICE market

PRE- OPENING-GENERAL MANAGER

01/2005 to 02/2007

InterContinental Hotel Al Khobar | Al-Khobar, Saudi Arabia

Promoted as Pre-opening Acting General Manager to take oversaw overall operation of hotel reporting to Area General Manager Inter-Continental hotels

Saudi Arabia

- \bullet Successfully soft open hotel established relations with key clients to gain market share by 12%
- Build InterContinental awareness by monitoring all marketing campaigns and forecast membership acquisitions and business development
- Recruited, hired trained initial personnel, working to establish key internal functions outline scope of positions for new organization
- Developed key performance goals for functions direct reports to corporate office of InterContinental Hotel
- Implement InterContinental employee recognition program which boosted productivity moral during opening stage
- Assisting to implement marketing strategy creation advertising initiatives to better promote facility to public as per InterContinental corporate policy secured status of key venue for MICE in Eastern province
- Developed implemented high-quality work environment as measured through employee satisfaction ratings

EDUCATION •

BBA | Hospitality Management, Architecture & Planning, Cornell University, Ithaca New York

09/1987

- Food Sciences,
- Introduction to Business Management, Financial Accounting, Marketing
- 1985-1987

High School Diploma | F&B Management, Hotel Computing Systems, Leadership *1987* Cornell University, Ithaca- New York

- Certification in F&B Management, Hotel Computing Systems, Leadership and Motivation, Planning for Profits: Food Service, Planning for Profit: Lodging, Front Office Operation.
- Summers Courses June 15-July 31-1987